Alright let's talk about mounting the rod into the reel.
Now we already have a mounted rod here.
This is a spinning outfit.
And if you'll notice the spinning outfit always sits below the reel seat.
So it's a nice balance.
It's easy to cast like that.
But once you've accomplished it you still have to thread the line through the guides so with a spinning outfit what you need to do is you need to open this bale up.
This is a line bale.
Take your line and basically just thread right through the guides.
Go all the way to the end.
Sometimes you'll drop the line and it'll come all the way out.
Alright so anyways there we go.
Now we simply close this bale up.
Reel up the slack and you've threaded the rod.
And if you'll notice the line always goes through this roller on the top.
Because that's what actually puts the line back on to the reel when you actually wind this.
It actually, this rotates around and puts the line back onto the spool.